Finding Aid for Theodore H. Hubbell Papers 1833-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Professional (primarily 1930s-1960s), 1890-1988
  - Correspondence, 1890-1988
    - Cabriles, J. Maldonado, 1938-1954 (Box 4)
    - Cantrall, Irving, 1939-1969 (Box 4)
    - Carr, Archie and Marjorie, 1939-1983 (Box 4)
    - Case, Ermine Cowles, 1934-1963 (Box 4)
    - D, 1946-1983 (Box 4)
    - Dice, Lee R., 1946-1948 (Box 4)
    - Dickinson, J.C., 1947-1959 (Box 4)
    - Dillon, Lawrence, 1947-1951 (Box 4)
    - Dowling, Herndon, 1947-1951 (Box 5)
    - Drake, Carl J., 1934-1953 (Box 5)
    - Dreisbock, R.R., 1941-1963 (Box 5)
    - E, 1939-1957 (Box 5)
    - Ellis, Robert J., 1951-1956 (Box 5)
    - Entomological Society of America, 1955-1971 (Box 5)
    - F, 1940-1985 (Box 5)
    - Fargo, William G., 1941-1957 (Box 5)
    - Fender, K.M., 1948-1953 (Box 5)
    - Foote, Ben, 1949-1955 (Box 5)
    - Friauf, James J., 1938-1955 (Box 5)
    - Fulton, B.B., 1947-1957 (Box 5)
    - G, 1943-1957 (Box 5)
    - Gaige, Frederick and Helen, 1915-1969 (Box 5)
    - Gloyd, Howard K., 1936-1965 (Box 5)
    - Goin, Coleman and Olive, 1947-1962 (Box 5)
    - Grahmam, Samuel A., 1951-1955 (Box 5)
    - Green, J.W., 1948-1951 (Box 5)
    - Guppy, Richard, 1949-1955 (Box 5)
    - Gurney, Ashley B., 1935-1955 (Box 5)
    - H, 1941-1957 (Box 5)
    - Hamilton, Rodgers B., 1948-1950 (Box 5)
    - Hebard, Morgan, 1934-1941 (Box 5)
    - Hobbs, Horton H., 1946-1962 (Box 5)
    - Howden, Henry F., 1952-1962 (Box 5)
    - Hubbs, Carl L., 1934-1957 (Box 5)
    - Hungerford, H.B., 1939-1956 (Box 5)
    - Hussey, Roland F., 1919-1964; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Hynes, Dennis, 1953-1959 (Box 5)
    - I, 1947-1956 (Box 5)
    - J, 1939-1956 (Box 5)
    - James, Maurice T., 1934-1956 (Box 5)
    - K, 1946-1956 (Box 6)
    - Kannowski, Paul B., 1953-1960 (Box 6)
    - Kimball, Charles B., 1957-1959 (Box 6)
    - Klots, Alexander B., 1956-1960 (Box 6)
    - Knull, James N., 1943-1951 (Box 6)
    - L, 1940-1964 (Box 6)
    - Laessle, Albert, 1947-1964 (Box 6)
    - M-Mc (Mac), 1947-1957 (Box 6)
    - Me-Mz, 1934-1957 (Box 6)
    - Man and the Biological World, 1949 (Box 6)
    - Mayr, Ernst, 1946-1956 (Box 6)
    - McMath, Robert, 1949-1950 (Box 6)
    - Michener, Charles D., 1949-1956 (Box 6)
    - Montgomery, B. Elwood, 1936-1962 (Box 6)
    - Moore, Sherman, 1947-1957 (Box 6)
    - Muesebeck, C.F.W., 1936-1950 (Box 6)
    - N, 1938-1956 (Box 6)
    - O, 1947-1965 (Box 6)
    - Olson, Ada, 1946-1980 (Box 6)
    - P, 1940-1964 (Box 6)
    - Peters, James A., 1953-1957 (Box 6)
    - Philip, Cornelius B., 1939-1955 (Box 6)
    - Princis, K., 1938-1946 (Box 6)
    - Q, 1956 (Box 6)
    - R, 1942-1961 (Box 6)
    - Ramstadt, Henry (with Alexander G. Ruthven), 1905-1907 (Box 6)
    - Rawson, George W., 1948-1951 (Box 6)
    - Ray, Eugene, 1945-1957 (Box 6)
    - Rehn, James A.G. (with Alexander G. Ruthven), 1907-1954 (Box 6)
    - Rogers, J. Speed, 1922-1955; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Ross, Herbert H., 1939-1957 (Box 6)
    - Ruthven,Alexander G., 1947-1959 (Box 6)
    - S-Sl, 1890-1966 (Box 6)
    - Sm-Sz, 1936-1983 (Box 6)
    - Sabrosky, Curtis W., 1938-1969 (Box 6)
    - Sanderson, Milton W., 1944-1961 (Box 6)
    - Schmidt, Erich, 1947-1952 (Box 6)
    - Sherman, Harley B., 1934-1976 (Box 6)
    - Slifer, Eleanor H., 1938-1958 (Box 6)
    - Re Steere, Joseph B., 1890-1964 (Box 6)
    - Stehr, William C., 1936-1957 (Box 6)
    - Steyskal, George, 1940-1962 (Box 6)
    - Stuart, Lawrence C., 1947-1983 (Box 6)
    - T, 1947-1964 (Box 7)
    - Townes, Henry K., 1955-1964; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - U, 1923-1957 (Box 7)
    - University of Michigan, 1919-1959 (Box 7)
    - V, 1943-1968 (Box 7)
    - Van Tyne, Josselyn, 1936-1957 (Box 7)
    - W, 1942-1980 (Box 7)
    - Wagner, Helmuth O., 1947-1985 (Box 7)
    - Walker, E.M., 1936-1957 (Box 7)
    - Wallace, H.K., 1945-1965 (Box 7)
    - Wallace, Herbert S., 1941-1956 (Box 7)
    - Watson, J.R., 1923-1932 (Box 7)
    - Weems, Howard V., 1949-1962 (Box 7)
    - Young, Frank N., 1941-1958 (Box 7)
    - Z, 1943-1959 (Box 7)
  - Projects, 1946-1972
    The Projects subseries consists of materials related to Hubbell's efforts to establish the field of biological systematics. These materials are arranged chronologically by project and are strongest in documenting his career during the 1960s when systematics became the buzz-word in zoology.
    - Historical Biogeography, 1946-1948 (Box 7)
    - Huron Mountain (MI), 1956-1961 (Box 7)
    - International Biological Program, 1966-1972
      - Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 7)
      - Hawaii Territorial Biology, 1967-1968 (Box 7)
      - Systematic Biology, 1964-1969; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Michigan Committee on Tropical Studies, 1957-1962; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Museum Survey Committee (Systematic Collections), 1966-1968; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - North Carolina Highlands, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Organization for Tropical Studies, 1966-1968
      - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 8)
      - Newsletters, 1967-1969 (Box 8)
      - Reports, 1966-1968 (Box 8)
    - Pacific Science Congress, 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Writings, 1911-1984
    The last subseries is a thin sampling of Hubbell's writings arranged chronologically. These range from highly specialized pieces on Florida fauna in the 1930s to a highly speculative piece on the "Unfinished Business and Beckoning Problems" in insect behavioral ecology penned in 1984. Of special interest is "An Introspective View of Taxonomy" in which Hubbell assesses his place in the field of entomology
    - Notebooks (Philippines, Washington, and Ann Arbor), 1911-1916 (Box 8)
    - Geology of Florida, circa 1927 (Box 8)
    - "A new Shrub-Inhabiting Species of Schisto-cerca from Central Florida,", 1928 (Box 8)
    - "Devil's Millhopper", circa 1928 (Box 8)
    - "Utopias,", March 1935 (Box 8)
    - "Myxobacteria", circa 1935 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1930s-1960 (Box 8)
    - UM Museum of Zoology Annual Reports, 1946-1956 (Box 8)
    - "An Introspective view of Taxonomy or What Have I Been Doing all these Years?,", 1965 (Box 8)
    - "Unfinished Business and Beckoning Problems (in Insect Behavioral Ecology),", 1984 (Box 8)